MATT ZAGER

SUMMARY

Copy editor, reporter, and print-page designer at daily newspapers for 17 years. Edited and proofread news stories for accuracy, clarity, grammar, and libel-law compliance. Wrote front-page headlines. Wrote daily-news stories on crime, government, courts, business, education, and elections.

SKILLS

Content management system, AP style, Microsoft Outlook, InDesign, Photoshop, HTML5, CSS3, responsive web design; strong foundation in Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, APIs, AJAX, JSON, and Chrome Developer Tools.

EXPERIENCE

Gannett, Neptune, NJ – Page editor/designer

JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2017

- Wrote headlines for three newspapers per day.
- Designed covers using grid systems, appropriate typography, and visual elements.
- Collaborated with managing editors on design and space issues.

Gannett, The Daily Journal, Vineland, NJ – Staff writer

FEBRUARY 2011 - JANUARY 2012

- Covered police and county government.
- Wrote six-10 stories per week.

Gannett, The Daily Journal, Vineland, NJ - Copy editor/page designer

SEPTEMBER 2006 - FEBRUARY 2011

• Copy-edited using AP style guide, wrote headlines, designed 1A.

The Daily Times — Copy editor/page designer

AUGUST 2004 - SEPTEMBER 2006

The Daily Times – *Staff writer*

AUGUST 2000 - AUGUST 2004

- Covered state-controlled schools and government in city of Chester.
- Wrote six-10 stories per week.

EDUCATION

West Chester University, PA – BA English Literature

PORTFOLIO

https://phillycodequestor.github.io/GDportfolio/